前情提要
欧文太太要招待很多宾客 她选了你
Mrs Owen is expecting a lot of guests. She chose you.
欢迎来到士兵岛
Welcome to Soldier Island.
隆巴德先生
Mr Lombard.
你似乎已经认定了我是某种样子的女人
You seem to be under the impression that I am a particular kind of woman.
但我保证 我绝不是
I assure you that I'm not.
它们是十个小士兵 那首诗歌里提到的
They're the ten little soldiers. You know, from the poem.
- 女士们 先生们!  - 是谁在说话?
- Ladies and gentlemen!  - Who is that?
你们被指控犯有以下罪名
You are charged with the following indictments!
菲利普·隆巴德 你谋杀了21个人
Philip Lombard, that you did murder 21 men.
他们到底在玩什么?
What the hell are they playing at?
真是充满恶意的荒唐话
Malicious nonsense.
西里尔 我真的试过想救他
Cyril, I really tried to save him.
我差点淹死
I almost drowned.
21个人?
21 men?
这房间里都是骗子 我是唯一说了实话的人
I am the only one telling the truth in a room full of liars.
是谁?
Who is it?
我们被断了退路
We are cut off.
是一窝被困住的老鼠
Rats in a barrel.
杏仁味
Almonds.
才不是什么杏仁味
Almonds be buggered.
是氰化物
Cyanide.
--==圣城家园SCG字幕组 http://hdscg.com/==--
仅供翻译交流使用, 禁止用于商业用途
协调: 影子
翻译: 凤梨酥
翻译: 無限月讀
翻译: 猫呗
翻译: 影子
校对: 影子
阿加莎·克里斯蒂作品
无人生还 第二集
你们没人动过?
None of you moved them?
- 没有  - 没动过
- No.  - No.
是你吗 医生?
Was it you, Doctor?
不是我
No.
罗杰斯太太是怎么死的?
How did Mrs Rogers die?
我也不知道
I have no idea.
你让她吃了什么药吗?
Did you give her something?
是 一种药效温和的镇定剂
Yes, a mild sedative.
会不会是量太多了?
Did you give her too much?
克莱索恩小姐 我告诉过你不要这么歇斯底里的
Miss Claythorne, I warned you against becoming hysterical.
是那首诗
It's the poem.
就是那首诗 你们没发现吗?
It's the poem, don't you see?
十个士兵小男孩 一个噎死了
Ten little soldier boys. One choked himself,
一个在睡梦中死去 还剩下八个!
one overslept himself and then there were eight!
原来桌上有十个小人 我们也有十个人 可是现在只剩下八个了
There were ten of these and ten of us and now there's eight.
将军 将军 你动过这些瓷像吗?
Oh, General. General, did you move the figures?
- 什么?  - 这些瓷像 你动过它们吗?
- What?  - The figures. Did you move the figures?
当然没有
No, course not.
也许是你自己吧 克莱索恩小姐
Perhaps it was you, Miss Claythorne.
是你发现的
You discovered it.
当然不是我了 我为什么要这么做?
Course it wasn't me. Why would I do that?
为了博得大家的注意? 你是不是很渴望被人关注呢 克莱索恩小姐?
To be the centre of attention? Do you crave attention, Miss Claythorne?
- 无论是那种关注都行吗?  - 你胡说什么?
- Any kind of attention?  - What are you talking about?
我们好好吃早餐行吗?
Shall we just have breakfast?
罗杰斯太太的遭遇真可怕
It was dreadful news about Mrs Rogers.
她是个优秀的厨娘
She was a wonderful cook.
真可惜
Such a shame.
鸡蛋是不是煮了正好四分钟?
Er, this egg is four minutes precisely, is it?
是的 夫人
Yes, madam.
罗杰斯 你有没有拿走两个瓷像?
Rogers, did you take away two of these figures?
没有 小姐
No, miss.
罗杰斯先生 请节哀 纳拉科特大概什么时候能来?
Condolences, Mr Rogers. When are you expecting Narracott?
上午或中午 先生 他过来的时间不太确定
Mid to late morning, sir. His timekeeping is somewhat erratic.
还有什么需要我的吗?
Will that be all?
没事了 谢谢你 罗杰斯 非常感谢
Yes. Thank you, Rogers. Thank you very much.
东尼·马斯顿年轻健康
Tony Marston was young and strong.
他不会是因为服用兴奋剂而死的
He didn't die from some stimulant.
可能是被人下毒了
Perhaps he was poisoned.
而罗杰斯太太可能是死于服药过量
And Mrs Rogers, perhaps she was given too much.
医生 你的药箱里都有什么药?
What drugs do you have in your medical bag, Doctor?
你为什么会带药箱来?
Why did you even bring it?
你是来做客的 又不是来工作的
You are a guest, it's not work.
说实话 我就是来工作的
Actually, it is work.
但出于医患保密协议 我本不应该说出来
I was trying to maintain some sort of professional discretion.
不过
However,
欧文太太患有女性精神类疾病
Mrs Owen suffers from female neuroses.
我的专长就是治疗女性疾病
My speciality is women's disorders.
欧文先生是请我来作为医生
Mr Owen engaged me in a professional capacity
- 照顾他妻子的  - 那你不再当外科医生了 是吗 医生?
- to tend to his wife.  - Gave up on the surgery, then, Doctor?
人不会无缘无故死去!
People do not just die out of nowhere for no reason!
他们会死 是因为有人对他们做了什么事!
They die because something was done to them by someone!
- 我要去查查你的包  - 你敢碰一下我的东西试试!
- I'm going to check your bag. - Don't you dare touch my possessions!
- 你有什么见不得人的东西吗?  - 我来检查怎么样?
- What have you got to hide?  - How about I do it?
我才不会像肮脏的罪犯一样任人搜查呢!
I'm not being searched like some grubby criminal!
那不如让将军和他一起去?
Then what if the General goes with him?
将军可是个体面的人!
He's an honourable man!
好吧! 不过这样的话 你们也得去搜查
Fine! But while you're at it, you might want to search
沃格雷夫法官的箱子
Judge Wargrave's case as well.
我知道我在哪里见过你了
I know where I've seen you before.
在我哈利街诊所楼下的那个小伙子
Chap who has the clinic beneath mine in Harley Street,
他是个治疗癌症的专家
he's a cancer specialist.
我就是在那里见到你的
That's where I saw you.
如果说谁的箱子里会有强效止痛药和镇定剂的话
If anyone has strong painkillers and sedatives in his case,
那就是沃格雷夫法官了
it's Judge Wargrave.
是这样吗 法官先生?
Is that true, Judge?
没错 我身体确实不好
I have had health problems, yes.
- 医生 你这样太过分了  - 不怪我 是你逼的
- Then that's very cruel, Doctor.  - Don't blame me. You pushed it.
将军 我们走吧?
General, shall we?
只有温和的镇定剂
Just mild sedatives.
我就是这么说的
As I said.
非常普通 没什么特别之处
Bog-standard. Nothing special.
我的手术很成功
My surgery was a success.
这里... 这所房子 这个小岛...
This... the house, the island...
本该是我修养的地方
is meant to be my recuperation.
吹吹海风
Sea air,
安安静静地
peace,
好好休息
and rest.
对不起 我真的很抱歉
Very sorry. I'm very sorry.
- 就到此为止吧  - 这事还没完呢
- Well, there's an end to it.  - Like hell it is.
为什么没人搜查她的东西?
Why shouldn't she be searched?
不是说男女平等吗
Equal rights for women.
我们看看你都有些什么东西
Let's see what you've got.
阿姆斯特朗医生 请冷静一点
Doctor Armstrong, control yourself, please.
你以为你自己是谁?
Who the hell do you think you are?
我是医生 你就是个秘书
I'm a doctor. You're a secretary.
有人动过它们
Somebody moved them.
肯定是这样
They did.
绝对有人动过那些瓷像
Someone did that.
你真的杀了那些人吗?
Did you really kill all those men?
是的 克莱索恩小姐 我确实杀了他们
Yes, Miss Claythorne. I did kill all those men.
还杀了别的人
And more.
为什么?
Why?
在当时 这样做才是聪明的选择
It seemed like a good idea at the time.
他们手里有我想要的东西 那一次是钻石
They had something I wanted. In this case, it was diamonds.
那可比几条人命更值钱
Worth more than a few lives.
你呢?
What about you?
你想要的是什么?
What did you want?
我差点淹死了
I nearly drowned.
我没能救下一个本应由我照看的小男孩
I failed to save a little boy in my care.
而我无时无刻不在为此感到愧疚
And there isn't one minute of every day that I'm not sorry for that.
你怎么就不内疚呢?
Why aren't you?
我知道我是什么样的人
I know what I am.
我也知道迟早有一天我要付出代价
I always knew it would catch up with me.
这一天到了
And here it is.
"我爱你 我爱你 我爱你
"I love you, I love you, I love you.
我思念你 你的吻 还有你的手爱抚我的感觉
I think about you and you kissing me, and your hands on me and in me,
你吻遍我每一寸肌肤 我无法忍受
and your mouth on my body and I cannot bear
你不在我身边的日子
that you are not with me now.
我希望 我盼望 我渴望你能陪伴我 亲爱的
I wish, I long, I crave for you, my darling,
我也觉得这样对亲爱的约翰太残忍了
and I feel so cruel to poor, dear John.
可是 亨利 太阳在你眼中升起又落下
The sun rises and sets in your eyes, Henry.
我爱你 我爱你
I love you. I love you.
我永远属于你"
I am yours."
大家都整装待发了 长官
The men are all ready for the whistle, sir.
士气也很高涨
Morale, fairly good.
来吧 让我帮您
Here. Er, let me.
亨利
Henry.
你一直都是我
You've been a great friend
和我妻子的好朋友
to my wife and I.
以后你就叫我约翰怎么样?
Perhaps you could call me John?
谢谢 约翰
Thank you, John.
先生 我和罗杰斯太太已经来这里一周了
Myself and Mrs Rogers were here for a week
除了来送货的纳拉克特之外
without seeing another soul
从来没有见过别人
apart from Narracott with the delivery, sir.
隆巴德
Lombard.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我们在这里干等尤利克·诺尔曼·欧文
We're sat around waiting for Ulick Norman Owen.
如果他一直都在这里呢?
What if he's been here all along?
这里有很多地方可供他藏身
Plenty of places he could be hiding.
等等我
Wait for me.
拜托了 拜托了 拜托了 别抖了
Please, please, please, just fucking stop. Stop.
停下 停下
Stop, stop,
停下吧 停下...
stop, stop...
这太吓人了!
This is barmy!
不可能有人藏在那下面
No-one could hide down there.
嘿 胖子 你有过被人追捕的感觉吗?
Ever get the feeling you're being hunted, Tubs?
别那么叫我 我才不胖
Stop calling me that. I ain't even fat.
而且我也没有过那种感觉
And, no, I don't.
是吗?
Really?
因为不论欧文先生是谁
Cos Mr Owen, whoever he may be,
他对我们都非常了解
knows a lot about us.
他可不了解我
Well, not about me.
爱德华·塞顿是个无赖 还是个同性恋
Edward Landor was a degenerate. He was a pansy.
他回牢房的时候自己从台阶上摔了下去
He fell down the steps into his cell.
你从没碰过他?
You never touched him?
那种肮脏下流的人 我都不愿意靠近他们
I wouldn't want to be near one of them dirty bastards.
来吧 胖子 跟上
Come on, Tubs, keep up.
将军?
General?
你收拾好行李了吗?
Is your suitcase ready?
她还是死了
She died.
在战后 死于西班牙流感
Of Spanish influenza, after the war.
谁?
Who?
我夫人 莱斯利
My wife Lesley.
一切都过去之后
After all that,
她竟然死于了西班牙流感
she died of the Spanish flu.
那时死了很多人
So many did.
我本应该像绅士一样退出...
I should've just stepped aside like a gentleman and...
让他们幸福地生活在一起的
just let them be happy.
回房子里来吧 将军
Do come back to the house, General.
你还没有把箱子拿下来
You haven't brought your case down yet
我们希望纳拉科特一来就马上离开
and we want to get away as soon as Mr Narracott arrives.
你得明白 纳拉科特不会回来了
He's not coming, Narracott, you know.
不会有人来找我们的
No-one's coming for us.
我们没法离开这个小岛了 这就是我们的结局
We won't be leaving the island. This is the end.
在知道一切都快要结束的时候 反而会有种解脱的感觉
It's a relief to come to the end, to know that it's over.
你现在可能还理解不了 但是总有一天...
You won't understand that yet but you will...
你会明白的
in time.
我想是您弄错了
I think you're quite mistaken.
会有船来接我们的 到时候我们大家都要等你了
The boat will come and we'll all be waiting for you.
克莱索恩小姐
Ah, Miss Claythorne.
真好
Good.
搬两把椅子过来 好吗?
Bring a couple of chairs, would you?
出什么事了?
What's going on?
怎么上午就喝这么多酒
It's a bit early to be on the sauce.
这一上午可够难熬的
It's been something of a morning.
嘿 嘿 嘘!
Hey. Hey, sh!
那个混蛋就在楼下 我听到了
Bastard's down there. I heard him.
哪个混蛋?
What bastard?
欧文
Owen.
我听见他的动静了
I can hear him moving about.
在马斯顿的房间里
Marston's room.
你在干什么?
What are you doing?
行军床
Camp bed.
我们得找个地方存放行军床...
We had to find somewhere to store it and...
- 而年轻人一般不会注意床下有什么  - 你...
- young men don't look under beds.  - But what...
还要行军床做什么? 你想干什么?
do you need a camp bed for? What were you planning?
我没法在自己房里睡觉了 不是吗?
Well, I can't sleep in my room, can I?
我妻子的缘故
Me wife.
是啊 当然了
Yeah, obviously. Of course.
我得找个别的地方收起来
I've got to find somewhere else to set up.
为什么? 我们都要走了
What for? We're all leaving.
你们也许要走了 可这是我的工作
Well, you might be. This is my job.
除非雇主解雇我 否则我哪也不能去
I can't go anywhere until my employer dismisses me.
你的雇主? 你的雇主是个疯子
Your employer? Your employer is insane.
即便如此 我也没别的事情可做
Be that as it may, I've got nothing else to go to.
那好吧 继续吧 罗杰斯
All right, then. Carry on, Rogers.
你知道他有枪吗?
Did you know he had a gun?
不知道
No.
停下 纳拉科特先生是个讲道理的人
Do stop. Mr Narracott seems a sensible man.
他会来的
He'll be here.
不得不说 我现在才明白
I must say, I understand now
你在如此低水准的学校教书的原因
why you teach in such a substandard establishment.
我想大多数学校
I'm just observing that most schools
都不想跟命案牵扯在一起
would not want to be associated with an inquest.
我不是在指责你 这些天互相指责已经够多了
I'm not accusing you. There's been quite enough of that already.
是的 太多了
Yes, there has. More than enough.
除了臭名昭著的隆巴德先生
Apart from the egregious Mr Lombard,
最可疑的罗杰斯
Rogers, who I find most dubious,
还有堕落的马斯顿先生
and the depraved Mr Marston,
其它都是胡扯
it's all nonsense.
每个人不过是尽了自己的职责
Everyone was simply doing their duty.
就和我一样
As was I.
和你一样?
As were you?
你昨晚什么都没说吗?
You didn't say anything last night?
那不是能说给绅士听的
It wasn't for gentlemen's ears.
比阿特丽斯·泰勒是照料我的女佣
But Beatrice Taylor was my maid of all work.
弃婴
Foundling girl.
战时被抛弃的
An unwanted,
你懂吧?
from the war, you know?
我相信她是个干净 有礼貌 谦逊的女孩
I believed her to be a clean, decent, modest girl.
我教给她针线活
I taught her needlework skills.
我们像家人一样
We had quite the little home.
后来她惹上了麻烦
But then she got herself into trouble.
有了孩子什么的
The family way.
就和她放纵的母亲一样
As her own loose mother had with her.
她求我帮她
She begged me for help.
理所当然的 我拒绝了她
Naturally, and quite properly, I refused.
布伦特小姐 求你!
Miss Brent, please!
求求你!
I beg you!
她后来怎样了?
What happened to her?
她卧轨了
She threw herself under a train.
她自杀了?
She killed herself?
甚至上了当地报纸
Even made the local paper.
后来成了茶余饭后的故事
And they turned it into some pot-boiling sentimental tale.
她求你帮她
She asked you for help.
如果你帮了她...
If you had helped her...
是她性格中的软弱驱使她这么干的
It was the weakness in her character which drove her actions.
能怪我吗?
Why should I be reproached?
让罗杰斯泡些茶
Ask Rogers for some tea.
要柠檬 不加奶
Lemon, not milk.
这样四处乱找没用的 如果要我说的话
It's a wild goose chase, if you ask me.
成年人鬼鬼祟祟 东躲西藏的 太可笑了
Grown man hiding and sneaking about. It's ridiculous.
可马斯顿被下了氰化物的毒
Marston was given cyanide, though.
- 不是吗 胖子?  - 氰化物?
- Wasn't he, Tubs?  - Cyanide?
我很肯定
I'm pretty sure of it.
我不知道... 你早上的时候很肯定
I don't know... You were convinced of it this morning.
是克莱索恩下的毒 我打赌
Claythorne, for the cyanide. I'd put money on it.
她看起来不像那样的人
She don't seem the type.
她就是那样的人
No, she's exactly the type.
那个老头呢 将军?
What about the old boy, the general?
从那儿回来的人都很危险 懂吧
Dangerous men come back, you know, from over there,
脑子都糊涂了
their noggins all scrambled.
好吧 那我们搜查每一个人
Oh, well, let's search everybody, then.
痴迷上帝的布伦特小姐... 还得搜查沃格雷夫
God-bothering Miss Brent... Let's search Wargrave.
谁 那个法官?
What, the Judge?
出了名的死刑法官
Well-known as a Hanging Judge.
经常判人死刑
He's infamous for the black square.
据说他判的每一例死刑执行时他都会去看
The story goes that he'd watch every execution he'd ordered.
胖子 你整个早上都在偷看阿姆斯特朗
Tubs, you've been looking sideways at Armstrong all morning
而现在每个人都有嫌疑了
and now everyone's fair game.
你先怀疑法官的
You suggested the Judge.
我只是随口一说 欧文先生在岛上
I was taking the piss. Mr Owen is on the island.
我会找到他的
And I'm going to find him.
你别听他瞎说
You don't want to pay attention to what he said.
他只想把水搅浑
He's just stirring the shit pot.
可我还是会查清楚
Well, I can stir it right back.
别看
Don't look.
是被杀的吗?
Someone did this?
这是流血事件
Well, it weren't no bleedin' accident.
这是谋杀
It's murder.
他说不会有人来的
He said no-one was coming for us.
他说这就是结局了
He said this was the end.
克莱索恩小姐
Miss Claythorne.
八个士兵小男孩 德文城里去猎奇
Eight little soldier boys travelling in Devon.
丢下一个命归西 八个只剩七
One said he'd stay there and then there were seven.
数数 法官
Count them, Judge.
数数
Count them.
萨拉 快去!
Sarah!
快跑!
Run!
找人帮忙!
Find help!
找条船! 快点!
A boat! Run!
萨拉!
Sarah!
萨拉 快去!
克莱索恩小姐!
Miss Claythorne!
我只想离开!
I just want to go!
你会淹死的!
You'll drown!
拜托
Please.
求你了
进来吧
Come inside.
过来
Come, come.
我抓住你了
I've got you.
别害怕 没事的
Don't worry, it's all right.
我说过欧文就在岛上
I told you Owen was on the island.
你凭什么这么肯定?
What made you so sure?
直觉
Instinct.
我们得理智些 按顺序来
We've got to be rational. Stick with procedure.
欧文先生是谁?
Who is this Owen?
还有欧文太太?
And Mrs Owen?
我觉得根本就没有欧文太太
I don't think there even is a Mrs Owen.
我们必然有什么共同点
We must all have something in common,
有人认识我们所有人
someone who knows us all.
那怎么可能?
Well, how can that be possible?
我能想象出认识医生...
I can imagine crossing paths with a doctor...
法官 可像隆巴德先生这样的人?
a judge, but someone like Mr Lombard?
现在我们都互相认识了 不是吗?
Well, we've crossed paths now. Haven't we?
隆巴德先生 布洛尔告诉我你有把手枪
Mr Lombard, Blore tells me that you have a revolver.
噢 胖子
Oh, Tubs.
你为什么有把枪?
Why have you got a gun?
他有把枪?
He's got a gun?
我去哪儿都带着
I carry it everywhere.
有人暗示说我会用到的
And it was implied that I might need it.
谁暗示你的?
Implied by whom?
我的客户需要一个能摆平局面的好手
My client needs a good man who can handle situations.
你客户是谁?
Who's your client?
欧文先生 尤利克·诺尔曼·欧文
Mr Owen. Ulick Norman Owen.
从没听说过他
Never heard of him.
可他听说过你
But he has heard of you.
奥德丽 把盒子拿来
Audrey, the box.
那很危险咯
It's dangerous, then.
我的客户相信会起事端
My client believes that it could become volatile.
我明白了
I see.
那么欧文先生打算要我怎么处理?
And how would Mr Owen wish me to proceed?
他相信你的判断
He leaves that to your discretion.
可提前警告你...
But forewarned is...
提前带上武器
Is fore-armed.
我明白了
I understand.
联系我说欧文太太雇佣我的也是那个人...
That's who got in touch with me about the job with Mrs Owen...
苏荷区的艾萨克·莫里斯
Isaac Morris in Soho.
苏荷区?
Soho?
欧文夫妇邀请我的 我从没听说过他们
I was invited here by the Owens, whom I've never heard of,
见一个共同的朋友...
to join a mutual friend...
卡尔明顿太太
Mrs Culmington.
据说这里休养身体的完美地点
The perfect place to recover, it said.
信封邮戳是伦敦苏荷区
The envelope was postmarked London, Soho.
道德沦丧
A sink of depravity.
上帝都不眷顾的荒漠
A godless desert of vice.
你怎么会来这的 布伦特小姐?
What brings you here, Miss Brent?
欧文太太写信给我
Mrs Owen wrote to me.
她对我的工作感兴趣
She was interested in my work.
底层社会女孩的道德教育
The moral education of girls of the lower orders.
需要教给她们谦逊礼貌
They have to be taught modesty and decency,
否则社会就将被无尽的弃婴吞没了
or society will be drowned in a rising tide of unwanted babies.
全都嗷嗷待哺
All squalling to be fed.
她想捐助我的事业
She wanted to contribute to my cause.
布洛尔先生呢?
Blore?
我收到一封信 来自尤利克·诺尔曼·欧文先生
I got a letter. From Ulick Norman Owen.
他景仰我在警队的地位
He was impressed by my standing in the force.
他说如果我能设法过来花些时间
He said if I could see my way clear to spending some time,
盯着点 他会慷慨酬谢我的
keeping an eye out, that he'd recompense me generously.
盯着点什么?
Keeping an eye out for what?
他说有人冒名顶替来的
He said that someone was here under false pretences.
他还提供了宾客名单
He also supplied a list of guests.
所有人
All of you.
这儿的每个人
Everyone here.
他没说的是隆巴德有把枪!
What he didn't say was that Lombard would have a gun!
唱片上是欧文先生的声音吗?
Is it Mr Owen's voice on the record?
有人认出来了吗?
Does anybody recognise it?
我们忘了这儿的枪了吗?
Are we forgetting about the gun here?
特么有个爱尔兰人带着枪呢!
There's a Fenian sat over there with a bloody gun!
- 别爆粗口!  - 交出来
- Don't blaspheme!  - Hand it over.
- 把枪交出来 隆巴德先生!  - 不可能
- Come on, surrender your weapon, Mr Lombard!  - Not a chance.
我能逼你交出来!
I could make you!
来试试啊
You can try.
艾萨克·莫里斯是欧文先生吗?
Is Isaac Morris Mr Owen?
不是
No.
否则我已经找到那个蠢货了
I'd have found that sweaty bucket of lard by now.
犹太人 不论何处有了问题
Jews. Wherever there's a problem,
都有犹太人在作怪
there's Jews at the bottom of it.
提醒我了
Something struck me.
不明白为何我以前没想到
I can't think why I didn't see it before.
尤利克·诺尔曼·欧文
Ulick Norman Owen.
尤纳·南希·欧文
Una Nancy Owen.
或者
Or..
U·N·欧文...
UN Owen...
就是佚名
is UNKNOWN.
也许是个谜语
It's a riddle, perhaps.
这什么意思?
What does it mean?
意味着隆巴德先生坚持认为
It means that Mr. Lombard is right to insist
凶手就在岛上是对的
that the killer is on the island.
他在外面肯定淋湿了
And he's getting very wet out there.
凶手不在外面
The killer's not out there.
凶手就在这
The killer is in here.
是我们中的一员
It is one of us.
这之前我们从未彼此见过 为何...
We've never met each other before now, why...
我怎么可能会杀人?
How could I possibly be capable?
谁都有可能 布伦特小姐
Oh, anyone is capable, Miss Brent.
40年来的判案教会了我这个道理
40 years on the criminal bench has taught me that.
- 罗杰斯  - 又来了 列出一个个嫌犯
- Rogers.  - Oh, here we go again. Lining up the next suspect.
记住我说的话 罗杰斯
You mark my words, Rogers.
他只不过是个油腔滑调的家伙
He's an oily bugger.
四处探头探脑
Slinking around.
晚餐时四处奔波
Going back and forth during dinner,
他有时间在马斯顿先生的酒水里加东西
he would have had time to put something into Mr. Marston's drink.
我听到他叫罗杰斯太太闭嘴
I heard him tell Mrs. Rogers to shut up.
她现在倒也是闭嘴了
Well, she's shut up now, isn't she?
就是他拿走瓷像的
He's the one moving the figures.
但是将军的死 其他人的死
But the General, the rest of us,
那个录音 这个别墅 为什么?
that record, this house, why?
罗杰斯行事狡猾
Rogers has got low cunning running through him
就像布莱顿那片岩石一样不靠谱
like Brighton through a stick of rock.
我们得盯着他
We need to watch him.
我对警察的所有信任
Any faith I ever had in the Thin Blue Line
在遇到你的一瞬间都消失无踪了 胖子
evaporated the second I met you, Tubs.
你敢再那么叫我一遍
You call me that one more time mate,
- 再叫一遍...  - 你会怎样?
- one more time...  - And you'll what?
我们...
We...
都被盯上了
are all being hunted.
这个岛上还有其他人
There's someone else on this island
等我找到他
and when I find him,
我就让他做我手下第22个亡魂
I'm going to make him number 22,
一枪毙了他
with a bullet right there.
天啊
Oh, God.
你怎么可以这么轻易地... 说出口?
How can you say that... so easily?
我一张嘴就说出来了
I just open my mouth and it comes out.
我看一看晚饭能吃什么
I'll see what can be done about supper.
还有些肝和腰子
There's some livers and kidneys.
也许可以做个派 上面浇点酱汁
Perhaps a pie with some good gravy.
那一定很美味 罗杰斯
That would be delicious, Rogers.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你 罗杰斯
Thank you, Rogers.
他做的派我一口都不会吃
Well, I ain't eating a mouthful of his pie.
晚安
Well, goodnight.
相信上帝
Trust in God.
但是我们也可以...
But perhaps also...
把门锁好
we should lock our doors.
耶和华是我的牧者 我将一无所求
The Lord is my shepherd, I shall not want.
他使我躺卧在青草地上
He maketh me to lie down in green pastures,
领我在可安歇的水边...
he leadeth me besides the still waters...
他使我的灵魂苏醒 为他的名引导我走义路
He leadeth me in the paths of righteousness for his name's sake.
我虽然行过...
Yay, though I walk through...
死荫的幽谷
the valley of the shadow of death...
也不怕遭害 因为你与我同在
I will fear no evil, for thou art with me.
不怕遭害
I will fear no evil.
不怕遭害 因为你与我同...
I will fear no evil for thou art...
不怕遭害 因为你与我同在...
I will fear no evil, thou art with me...
都起来!
Get up!
我刚才在找他
I was looking for him.
我想要杯咖啡 我看了一下...
I wanted a coffee. I looked...
然后看到了这个
and I found this.
不是我干的
It wasn't me.
我只不过想要一杯咖啡 不是我干的...
I just wanted a damn coffee, it wasn't me...
他死了一整晚了
He's been here all night.
七个士兵小男孩 伐树砍枝不顺手
Seven little soldiers chopping up sticks,
斧劈两半一命休 七个只剩六
one chopped himself in half and then there were six.
所以她说得对
So she's right.
和那首诗一样
It is the poem,
但是他错了 欧文无名先生
but he's fucked, Mr Unknown Owen,
六个士兵小男孩 玩弄蜂房惹蜂怒
because six little solder boys played with a hive.
飞来一蛰命呜呼 六个只剩五
A bumble bee stung one and then there were five
这里根本没有蜂房 也没有蜜蜂
and there is no hive here and there are no bees,
所以你准备怎么办 欧文无名先生? 你错了!
so what are you going to do now, Mr Unknown Owen? You're fucked!
你错...
You're fu...
我去穿衣服
I will get dressed,
我们都去穿衣服...
we will all get dressed...
然后我去泡咖啡
and I will make coffee.
- 布伦特小姐 我们走吧?  - 好的
- Miss Brent, shall we?  - Yes.
该死 真该死
Shit. Shit the bed.
我们得找点东西把他包起来
We need to find something to wrap him up with
不然到处都是血
or he's going to go everywhere.
咖啡
Coffee.
恐怕没有牛奶了
There's no milk, I'm afraid.
这个人是不是...
Does this person...
要杀掉所有人?
mean to kill us all?
我猜是的
I believe so, yes.
我丢了一个毛线球
I've lost a ball of wool.
我为此很懊恼
I'm quite ridiculously distressed about it.
只是个毛线球...
It's only wool...
我太累了
I'm so very tired.
把咖啡喝完 布伦特小姐
Drink your coffee, Miss Brent.
我给你拿个蜡烛过来照明
I'll bring you a candle to see by.
谢谢你 亲爱的
Thank you, dear.
我再去泡些咖啡
I'll make some more.
沃格雷夫法官 我觉得我...
Judge Wargrave, I feel I...
该向你道歉...
owe you an apology for...
我不该那么不可饶恕地告诉大家你的疾病
exposing your illness in such an unforgiveable fashion.
大家都有点失控了 可以理解
We're all feeling a little ragged. Understandably.
你对其他人有什么看法?
What's your opinion of the others?
我没有看法
I haven't really formed one.
我谁都不相信
I don't trust any of them.
布洛尔 隆巴德那个混蛋 克莱索恩
Blore. That bastard Lombard. Claythorne.
布伦特小姐和她那对宗教的狂热
Miss Brent and her religious mania.
但是你和我...
But you and I...
都有犀利的头脑
we have sharp minds.
都很有智慧
Actual intellects.
我们应该待在一起
We should stay together.
好的
Very well.
天...
Oh, Go...
给你 给你
Here. Here.
多谢
Thank you.
和小孩子一样弄得到处都是
Dribbling down myself like a child.
克莱索恩小姐在做咖啡...
Miss Claythorne's making the coffee...
得有人看着她
she should be watched.
对
Right.
你把台阶弄干净
You do the stairs,
我去把柴房地板上的内脏弄干净
I'm going to wash the guts out of the woodstore.
我来吧?
Can I?
我很喜欢做家务
I rather enjoy domestic tasks.
很舒缓
They are soothing.
平和
Normal.
的确
Indeed.
我马上回来
I'll just be a moment.
好的
All right.
蜜蜂一蛰
Stung by a bee.
六个只剩五
And then there were five.
我想 罗杰斯死了 得我来想午餐吃什么了
Well, I suppose, with no Rogers, I should think about lunch.
我已经饿得要死了
I could eat a scabby horse.
你真的饿了?
You're actually hungry?
我干了重活... 处理罗杰斯的尸体
That was heavy work... dealing with Rogers.
你提议吃午餐了
And you're the one that suggested lunch.
只因为一般都是这个点吃午餐
Only because it's what one does at this time of day,
但是我不饿 你怎么就饿了?
but I'm not hungry, how could you possibly be hungry?
喂 你!
Oi, you!
别瞎暗示...
Don't go implying...
诽谤我... 我和
Casting aspersions... I've got not,
我和这事没关系
I've got nothing to do with this.
我和这一点关系都没有
I've got nothing to do with any of it.
只不过因为我饿了
Just because I said I was hungry.
我确实饿了 这根本证明不了什么!
I am hungry, it doesn't prove a single thing!
我去换衣服
I'm going to get dressed.
我整个早晨
The whole morning,
拖着罗杰斯的尸体 清理内脏
dragging Rogers around, clearing up guts,
忙的连喝杯茶尿个尿的时间都没有 而你...
without so much as a cup of tea to wet me whistle, and you..
- 你看着我的样子就像...  - 冷静
- you look at me like I...  - Calm down.
你有种 女人
You've got some front, love.
你胆子还真够大的
You've got some right brass neck.
别一个人下楼
Don't go downstairs on your own.
除非有那俩陪着你
Not with those two.
谁 沃格雷夫和阿姆斯特朗?
What, Wargrave and Armstrong?
你在这里等我
You wait up here for me.
房间是锁着的 所以一定有主钥匙
It was locked. Which means there must be a master key.
罗杰斯一定有主钥匙
Rogers must have had a master key.
- 是你们俩处理他的尸体的!  - 是你发现的!
- You two dealt with the body!  - And you found it!
还是说根本是你杀的?
Or did you?
你跟女人似的尖叫
You shrieking like a woman,
那可不是什么成熟的表现吧?
was that a bit of amateur dramatics, was it?
我没有杀罗杰斯
I did nothing to Rogers.
也没有拿走什么主钥匙
I didn't take any master key,
我们根本不知道到底有没有那钥匙
we don't even know if there is a master key,
我们只知道你说枪被偷了
and we only had your word that the gun was stolen,
- 也许就是你偷的  - 我干嘛要偷自己的枪?
- you could've taken it.  - Why would I steal my own gun?
我不知道你为什么要做这些事 隆巴德
I don't know why you'd do anything, Lombard,
我不知道你为什么要杀
I don't know why you killed
罗杰斯 布伦特小姐 麦克阿瑟
Rogers or Miss Brent or MacArthur.
- 我没有杀他们  - 你的确可以这么说 对吧?
- I didn't kill them.  - Well, you would say that, wouldn't you?
就像你说你的枪被偷了一样
Just like you'd say that your gun was stolen.
你真是个顶级
You really are a first-class,
五星级
five-star,
闪闪特么发光的白痴
solid gold fucking moron.
拜托! 还有女士在场!
Please! The lady!
虚实并用的骗术
Double bluff.
什么 胖子?
What, Tubs?
你为什么要偷自己的枪 阿姆斯特朗说得对
Why you would steal your own gun. Armstrong's got a point.
这都是谜题把戏 烟幕弹和镜花水月 就是虚实并用的骗术
It's all riddles and games, smoke and mirrors, double bluff.
你是最后一个下楼的人
You were the last one down.
最后一个
The last one.
比其他人晚了很多
Ages behind everyone else.
什么事耽误了你那么久?
What, what took you so long?
我不想说
I don't care to say.
你杀了罗杰斯
You killed Rogers.
你拿走了主钥匙 上床睡觉
You took the master key, you went to bed,
确保我们都下了楼
you made sure all of us were downstairs,
然后去了我的房间 拿走了我的枪
then you got in my room and took my gun.
我的枪在你手上 你个蠢货
You have my gun, you little prick.
隆巴德! 注意用词
Lombard! For heaven's sake.
我没杀罗杰斯
I never killed Rogers and
也没拿钥匙和你的枪!
I ain't got your key or your sodding gun!
那你为什么那么慢?
Then what took you so long?
如果你不是在我房间里偷枪的话
If you weren't in my room, stealing my gun,
怎么会是最后一个到的?
then why were you last down?
你非要问的话 我在蹲厕所!
I was in the bloody lavvy, if you must know!
便秘
Constipated.
好吧
Oh, yes.
都使劲笑吧
Yeah, laugh it up.
又不搞笑
It's not funny.
肯定是吃坏了肚子
Bound up something rotten.
坐那儿出了一身臭汗
Sat there in a muck sweat.
所以不是我
So it weren't me.
我们都有嫌疑
It could have been any of us.
钥匙可能在任何人手里
Any one of us could have had the key.
枪也可能在任何人手里
Any one of us could have the gun.
这是唯一可以确认的方法
It is the only way to be sure.
也不是只针对你一个人的
It's not like you have been singled out.
我们都会遭此待遇
We're all getting the same.
没有钥匙
No key.
没有枪
No gun.
轮到你了 克莱索恩小姐
Now you, Miss Claythorne.
好的
Of course.
我只是想仔细搜搜
I'm just being thorough.
你喜欢雨果叔叔 对吧?
You like Uncle Hugo, don't you?
对
I do.
我... 爱上他了
I'm... in love with him.
我爱他爱得痛彻心腑
I love him so much it hurts.
真笨 女孩子都很笨
Silly. Girls are silly.
我会嫁给他的
And I'm going to marry him.
我听妈妈说他没钱结婚
I heard Mummy say he couldn't afford to get married.
我会想到办法的 西里尔
Well, I'll find a way, Cyril.
- 如果你嫁给雨果叔叔...  - 是等我嫁给雨果的时候
- If you marry Uncle Hugo...  - When I marry Hugo.
你会当我的婶婶吗?
Will you be my aunt?
会的
I will.
维拉婶婶
Aunt Vera.
想想我们会怎么玩
And what fun we'll have.
圣诞 生日 还有暑假
Christmas and birthdays and summer holidays.
野营 派对
Picnics. Parties.
骑马
Pony rides.
等拥有一切 我们会有多幸福呀!
How happy we'll be when we have everything!
西里尔!
Cyril!
为什么隆巴德不来搜?
Why isn't Lombard doing this?
我和布洛尔觉得把你俩分开比较好
Blore and I thought it a good idea to keep you two apart.
好吧 克莱索恩小姐
Well, well, Miss Claythorne.
隆巴德先生
Mr Lombard.
菲利普
Philip.
维拉
Vera.
都没有
Nothing.
我们得搜遍其它所有的房间
We'll search the rest of the house. Every room.
我们身处地狱...
We're in hell...
要为自己造过的孽接受惩罚
and we're being punished for what we've done.
他拒绝戴布罩
He refused the hood.
至今还让我心惊
He haunts me still.
看看他们 他们之间肯定有什么问题
Look at them. There is something going on between them.
很快就会有人来救我们了 肯定会的
Someone has to come for us soon. They have to.
我觉得我们被监视了
I reckon we're being watched.
没错
We are.